Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you another great lesson for all of you who are interested in
今天，我们为所有对购物感兴趣的朋友带来另一堂精彩的课程。
shopping.
购物。
Especially those of you who are interested in shopping for a car.
特别是那些对买车感兴趣的朋友。
A car, exactly.
买车，没错。
So we're going to give you some great language about describing a car or characteristics
所以我们将教大家一些描述汽车或汽车特性的实用语言。
of a car.
汽车的特性。
Yep.
是的。
And also some really interesting language for shopping.
还有一些关于购物的非常有趣的语言。
Yes, especially buying something really big and expensive.
是的，尤其是买一些又大又贵的东西。
Yeah, like a car.
对，比如汽车。
Yeah.
嗯。
So before we listen to our dialogue, let's take a look at vocabulary preview.
所以在听对话之前，我们先来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
On vocabulary preview today, we're bringing you two words.
今天的词汇预览，我们带来两个词。
The first one is vehicle.
第一个是 vehicle。
Vehicle.
Vehicle。
车辆。
Vehicle.
So, again, a vehicle is a machine, right?
所以，再说一次，车辆是一种机器，对吧？
Right.
对。
A machine that carries people from one place to another.
一种把人从一个地方运到另一个地方的机器。
So it's important to say that a vehicle could be an airplane.
所以重要的是要说，车辆可以是飞机。
A car.
汽车。
A boat.
船。
Yeah, that's a vehicle.
是的，那是一种车辆。
Our second word is sedan.
我们的第二个词是轿车。
Sedan.
轿车。
So a sedan is a type of car.
所以轿车是一种汽车类型。
Exactly.
没错。
It's a type of car with four doors that can fit five people inside.
它是一种有四扇门、可容纳五人的汽车。
So to make it more clear, most taxis are sedans.
为了更清楚地说，大多数出租车都是轿车。
Exactly.
没错。
Right?
对吧？
They have four doors, five people can fit in there, including the driver.
它们有四扇门，包括司机在内可以坐五个人。
Except taxis in Mexico.
除了墨西哥的出租车。
They're not sedans?
它们不是轿车吗？
They're little beetles.
它们是小甲壳虫车。
Oh.
哦。
They're Volkswagen beetles.
它们是大众甲壳虫。
Okay.
好吧。
So those are not sedans.
所以那些不是轿车。
But yeah, most countries have sedans as taxis.
但没错，大多数国家的出租车都是轿车。
To give you some examples, like a Toyota Corolla or a Toyota Camry is a sedan.
举个例子，像丰田卡罗拉或丰田凯美瑞就是轿车。
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
Maybe like a Volkswagen Jetta.
也许像大众捷达。
Is that a...
那是……
A Jetta, yeah.
捷达，对。
A Jetta is a sedan.
捷达是轿车。
Yeah.
是的。
Now we can listen to our dialogue, and it's going to be at a normal speed the first time,
现在我们来听对话，第一次会以正常速度播放，
but you don't have to worry about it.
但你不用担心。
We'll come back and teach you some of the important words from the dialogue.
我们会回来教你对话中的一些重要词汇。
Hi there, can I help you folks?
嗨，有什么能帮你们的吗？
I'm just browsing, seeing what's on the lot.
我只是随便看看，看看车场里有什么。
My daughter wants a car for her birthday, you know how it is.
我女儿想要一辆车作为生日礼物，你懂的。
Dad, I'm 16 already, and I'm like the only one at school who doesn't have a car.
爸，我已经16岁了，学校里好像就我没车了。
She's right, you know.
她说得对，你知道吗。
Kids these days all have cars.
现在的孩子都有车。
Let me show you something we just got in, a 1996 sedan, excellent gas mileage.
让我给你看看我们刚到的车，一辆1996年的轿车，油耗很低。
It has dual airbags and anti-lock brakes, a perfect vehicle for a young driver.
它配有双安全气囊和防抱死刹车，对年轻司机来说很完美。
Dad, I love it.
爸，我喜欢这辆车。
It's awesome.
太棒了。
Can we get this one, please?
我们能买这辆吗？
I see.
我明白了。
What can you tell me about this one?
你能给我介绍一下这辆吗？
Oh, that's just an old World War II tank that we used for TV commercials.
哦，那只是一辆二战时期的老坦克，我们用来拍电视广告的。
Now about this sedan...
现在来看看这辆轿车……
Whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
哇，哇，等一下。
Tell me more about this tank.
再多说说这辆坦克。
Well, sir, if you are looking for quality and safety, then look no further.
先生，如果您追求品质和安全，那就不用再看了。
Three inches of reinforced steel protect your daughter from short-range missile attacks.
三英寸厚的强化钢能保护您的女儿免受短程导弹袭击。
Does the sedan protect her from missile attacks?
这辆轿车能保护她免受导弹袭击吗？
It does not.
不是这样的。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不知道。
Let me sleep on it.
让我考虑一晚上。
Did I mention the tank is a tank?
我有没有说过那坦克就是辆坦克？
I'll take it.
我买了。
Dad!
爸爸！
I think she's really lucky.
我觉得她真的很幸运。
Really?
真的吗？
She's getting a tank to go to school.
她要开坦克去上学。
How awesome is that?
那有多酷啊？
I would be so embarrassed if I had to drive to school in a tank.
如果我得开坦克去上学，我会尴尬死的。
It's like the coolest car.
它可是最酷的车。
Oh, you're such a boy.
哦，你真是个男孩子。
All right, a surprising ending to a relatively easy shopping day.
好吧，相对轻松的购物日却有个出人意料的结局。
Yeah.
是啊。
Let's take a look at some language that we saw in our dialogue on Language Takeaway.
让我们看看对话中出现的一些语言点，在语言要点环节。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
We have four words for you today.
今天我们有四个单词要学。
The first one is gas mileage.
第一个是燃油效率。
Gas mileage.
燃油效率。
油耗。
Gas mileage.
So gas mileage is how many miles you can travel on a gallon or liter of gasoline.
所以油耗是指每加仑或每升汽油能行驶多少英里。
Well, you know what's interesting?
嗯，你知道什么有趣吗？
In some English-speaking countries like Australia, New Zealand, Canada, we use kilometers to
在一些英语国家，比如澳大利亚、新西兰、加拿大，我们用公里来衡量距离，
measure distance, but we still talk about gas mileage.
但我们仍然说油耗。
Yeah.
是啊。
I guess you can't say gas kilomileage.
我想你不能说公里油耗。
No.
不能。
Or something like that.
或者类似的东西。
But yeah, it's basically how many kilometers or how many miles you can travel on a tank
不过，基本上就是一箱油能跑多少公里或多少英里。
or on a liter or gallon of gas.
或者每升或每加仑汽油能跑多少。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
The next word is airbags.
下一个词是安全气囊。
Airbags.
安全气囊。
These are like big bags of air that fill up and come out of the car when there's a crash.
它们就像大袋子，里面充满空气，发生碰撞时会从车里弹出来。
Right.
对。
So that way you don't hit your head against the steering wheel or something like that.
这样你就不会把头撞到方向盘或类似的东西上。
So they protect you.
所以它们能保护你。
Right.
对。
I've heard that Volvo has like 18 airbags now in their cars.
我听说沃尔沃现在车里大概有18个安全气囊。
They are very safe cars, you know.
它们是非常安全的车，你知道的。
Like a big balloon.
就像一个大气球。
Okay.
好的。
Our third word today is brakes.
我们今天的第三个词是刹车。
Brakes.
刹车。
So what are brakes?
那么什么是刹车？
Brakes are little...
刹车是小小的……
What are brakes?
什么是刹车？
Brakes are what make your car stop.
刹车就是让你的车停下来的东西。
Okay.
好的。
So they're the little machines maybe that stop your car?
所以它们可能是让车停下来的小机器？
Yeah.
是的。
They're on the wheels.
它们在轮子上。
Yeah.
是的。
They make your car stop.
它们能让你的车停下来。
You have brakes on your bike.
你的自行车上有刹车。
Yes.
是的。
On your car, etc.
在你的车上等等。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Our last word today on Language Takeaway, reinforced.
今天《语言小贴士》的最后一个词是“reinforced”。
Reinforced.
Reinforced。
So we have some examples of how we use reinforced because it's a little bit weird.
我们有一些关于如何使用“reinforced”的例子，因为它有点奇怪。
Yeah.
是的。
These will help you understand the meaning.
这些会帮助你理解意思。
Example one.
例子一。
So I reinforced all the walls.
所以我加固了所有墙壁。
There's no way they're going to fall down.
它们绝对不会倒塌。
Example two.
例子二。
This plastic is reinforced with glass, so it's both light and strong.
这种塑料用玻璃加固了，所以既轻又坚固。
So basically anything that's reinforced is made stronger.
所以基本上任何被加固的东西都变得更坚固。
Perfect.
完美。
Reinforced steel, reinforced table, anything.
加固钢材、加固桌子，任何东西都可以。
Okay.
好的。
Great.
太棒了。
So now we can listen to our dialogue again.
现在我们可以再听一遍对话。
You can practice all these words that we just talked about and we'll come back shortly.
你可以练习我们刚刚讨论过的所有单词，我们一会儿就回来。
Hi there.
嗨，你们好。
Can I help you folks?
有什么需要帮忙的吗？
I'm just browsing, seeing what's on the lot.
我只是随便看看，看看车场里有什么。
My daughter wants a car for her birthday.
我女儿想要一辆车作为生日礼物。
You know how it is.
你知道的，就是这样。
Dad, I'm 16 already and I'm like the only one at school who doesn't have a car.
爸，我已经16岁了，而且我好像是学校里唯一没有车的人。
She is right, you know.
她说得对，你知道的。
Kids these days all have cars.
现在的孩子都有车。
Let me show you something we just got in.
我给你看看我们刚到的货。
A 1996 sedan.
一辆1996年的轿车。
Excellent gas mileage.
油耗很低。
It has dual airbags and anti-lock brakes.
它配有双安全气囊和防抱死刹车。
A perfect vehicle for a young driver.
对年轻司机来说，这车很完美。
Dad, I love it.
爸，我好喜欢。
It's awesome.
太棒了。
Can we get this one, please?
我们能买这辆吗？
I see.
我明白了。
What can you tell me about this one?
你能告诉我这辆怎么样吗？
Oh, that's just an old World War II tank that we use for TV commercials.
哦，那只是一辆二战时期的旧坦克，我们用来拍电视广告的。
Now about this sedan.
现在来说说这辆轿车。
Whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
哇，哇，等一下。
Tell me more about this tank.
多跟我说说这辆坦克。
Well, sir, if you are looking for quality and safety, then look no further.
先生，如果您追求品质和安全，那就不用再看了。
Three inches of reinforced steel protect your daughter from short-range missile attacks.
三英寸厚的强化钢能保护您的女儿免受短程导弹袭击。
Does the sedan protect her from missile attacks?
这辆轿车能保护她免受导弹袭击吗？
It does not.
不能。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不知道。
Let me sleep on it.
让我考虑一下。
Did I mention the tank is a tank?
我有没有说过这辆坦克就是辆坦克？
I'll take it.
我买了。
Dad.
爸。
So we have a couple of interesting phrases to talk about shopping.
所以我们有一些关于购物的有趣短语。
Right.
对。
Let's look at these in Fluency Builder.
我们来看看这些在流利度构建器里的内容。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
The first one today is, I'm just browsing.
今天第一个是，我只是随便看看。
I'm just browsing.
我只是随便看看。
This is a really useful phrase because usually salespeople will come up to you and ask you,
这是一个非常有用的短语，因为通常销售人员会走过来问你：
can I help you?
需要帮忙吗？
Are you interested in something?
您对什么感兴趣吗？
Yeah.
是的。
And you're just looking.
而你只是在看。
Yeah, you maybe don't really want to buy today.
是的，你可能今天并不想买。
Right.
对。
So you're just, I'm just browsing.
所以你就只是，我只是随便看看。
So then they'll just leave you alone.
然后他们就不会打扰你了。
Yeah, they won't bother you as much.
是的，他们不会那么烦你了。
Yeah, it's a good, good phrase.
嗯，这是个好短语。
Another good phrase.
另一个好短语。
Sleep on it.
考虑一下。
So we have some examples of how we use sleep on it.
所以我们有一些关于如何使用“考虑一下”的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
I don't know if we should buy that house.
我不知道我们是否应该买那栋房子。
It's perfect for us, but it's so expensive.
它对我们来说很完美，但是太贵了。
Let's sleep on it.
我们考虑一晚上吧。
Example two.
例子二。
Why don't you sleep on it and tell me tomorrow?
你为什么不考虑一下，明天再告诉我？
Example three.
例子三。
This is a bit more than what I can afford.
这有点超出我的承受能力。
Let me sleep on it.
让我考虑一下。
To sleep on it means to...
“考虑一晚上”的意思是……
Like to think about it overnight.
想考虑一晚上。
To think about it.
考虑一下。
Yeah.
是的。
Right.
对。
So maybe you want to buy this really expensive car.
所以也许你想买这辆非常贵的车。
But you need to think about it.
但你需要考虑一下。
Right.
对。
So you'll sleep on it.
所以你会先睡一觉再决定。
So yeah.
所以是的。
You go home, sleep on it, think about it twice, and then make a decision.
你回家，睡一觉再考虑，三思而后行，然后做决定。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, great words and great dialogue.
好的，很棒的词汇和对话。
Yeah, I love this dialogue.
是啊，我喜欢这段对话。
Yeah, it's kind of funny.
嗯，有点搞笑。
So we could listen to it again, and then we'll come back and talk a little bit about it.
我们可以再听一遍，然后回来讨论一下。
Hi there, can I help you folks?
你们好，有什么需要帮忙的吗？
I'm just browsing, seeing what's on the lot.
我只是随便看看，看看车场里有什么。
My daughter wants a car for her birthday.
我女儿想要一辆车作为生日礼物。
You know how it is.
你知道的。
Dad, I'm 16 already, and I'm like the only one at school who doesn't have a car.
爸，我已经16岁了，而且我好像是学校里唯一没有车的人。
She's right, you know.
她说得对，你知道的。
Kids these days all have cars.
现在的孩子都有车。
Let me show you something we just got in.
我给你看看我们刚到的货。
A 1996 sedan.
一辆1996年的轿车。
Excellent gas mileage.
油耗很低。
It has dual airbags and anti-lock brakes.
它配有双安全气囊和防抱死刹车。
A perfect vehicle for a young driver.
对年轻司机来说，这车很完美。
Dad, I love it.
爸，我好喜欢。
It's awesome.
太棒了。
Can we get this one, please?
我们能买这辆吗？
I see.
我明白了。
What can you tell me about this one?
你能告诉我这辆车的什么信息？
Oh, that's just an old World War II tank that we used for TV commercials.
哦，那只是一辆二战时期的旧坦克，我们用来拍电视广告的。
Now about this sedan.
现在来说说这辆轿车。
Whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
哇，哇，等一下。
Tell me more about this tank.
多跟我说说这辆坦克。
Well, sir, if you are looking for quality and safety, then look no further.
先生，如果您追求品质和安全，那么不用再找了。
Three inches of reinforced steel protect your daughter from short-range missile attacks.
三英寸厚的强化钢可以保护您的女儿免受短程导弹袭击。
Does the sedan protect her from missile attacks?
这辆轿车能保护她免受导弹袭击吗？
It does not.
不能。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不知道。
Let me sleep on it.
让我考虑一下。
Did I mention the tank is a tank?
我有没有说过这辆坦克就是辆坦克？
I'll take it.
我买了。
Dad!
爸！
So, Marco, have you ever driven a tank?
那么，马可，你开过坦克吗？
I mean, I know you're in the Army.
我是说，我知道你在陆军服役。
Yeah, actually I did.
是的，实际上我开过。
I did drive a tank before.
我以前确实开过坦克。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, really old one.
是啊，很老的那种。
Kind of like a World War II type tank.
有点像二战时期的坦克。
But yeah, they're really fun and interesting.
不过确实很有趣。
It's not like driving a normal car.
开起来跟普通车不一样。
You have pedals.
有踏板。
So there's no steering wheel?
那没有方向盘吗？
No, no, no.
没有，没有。
You have levers.
有操纵杆。
And what many people don't know is that actually tanks are manual transmissions.
很多人不知道，坦克其实是手动挡的。
You have to change gears.
你得换挡。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
And it's really hard to change gears on those things.
而且那些东西换挡特别难。
And what's the gas mileage like in a tank?
一箱油的油耗怎么样？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Maybe like five miles per gallon.
大概每加仑五英里吧。
They run on diesel, which is a different type of fuel, right?
它们烧柴油，那是另一种燃料，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, well, very cool.
好吧，挺酷的。
I never knew that my podcast partner had driven a tank.
我从不知道我的播客搭档开过坦克。
That's pretty awesome.
那真是太棒了。
Yeah, well, it was fun, definitely.
是啊，嗯，确实挺有意思的。
And I hope I get to do it again someday.
而且我希望有一天还能再玩一次。
All right.
好吧。
Well, guys, have you ever driven a tank?
那么，各位，你们开过坦克吗？
Or a submarine or any type of armored vehicle?
或者潜艇，或者任何类型的装甲车？
Yeah.
是的。
You can find out more about it at our website, EnglishPod.com.
你可以在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上了解更多信息。
Right.
没错。
We'll be there to answer all your questions.
我们会在那里回答你们的所有问题。
I'll also be there to maybe post some more crazy stories.
我也许还会在那里分享一些更疯狂的故事。
Or some pictures of a tank.
或者一些坦克的照片。
Yeah, maybe.
嗯，也许吧。
Yeah.
是的。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
We'll see you there.
我们到时候见。
Until then, it's goodbye.
在那之前，再见。
Cheers.
干杯。